export const NetworkingFundamentals = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question:
      "What is the main difference between a hub and a switch in a network?",
    options: [
      "Hubs connect devices electrically, while switches connect them logically.",
      "Hubs are more expensive than switches.",
      "Hubs are faster than switches,",
      "Hubs can filter network traffic.",
    ],
    answer:
      "Hubs connect devices electrically, while switches connect them logically.",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "Which of the following is NOT a common type of network cable?",
    options: ["Coaxial cable", "Fiber optic cable", "USB cable", "Cat6 cable"],
    answer: "USB cable",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question:
      "When troubleshooting a network connection issue, which of the following tools would be MOST helpful in identifying the problem?",
    options: [
      "A word processing program",
      "A web browser",
      "A ping utility",
      "A video editing software",
    ],
    answer: "A web browser",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question:
      "What is the purpose of using a crossover cable when connecting two network devices?",
    options: [
      "To connect a computer to a switch.",
      "To connect two switches together.",
      "To connect a computer to a printer.",
      "There is no need for a crossover cable in modern networks.",
    ],
    answer: "To connect two switches together.",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: "What is the subnet mask used for in an IP address?",
    options: [
      "Defines the network portion of the IP address.",
      "Determines the maximum number of devices on a network.",
      "Identifies the specific device within the network.",
      "Both (a) and (b).",
    ],
    answer: "Both (a) and (b).",
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question:
      "Which of the following protocols is responsible for ensuring reliable data delivery by breaking data into packets and acknowledging their receipt?",
    options: ["HTTP", "HTTPS", "SMF", "TCP"],
    answer: "TCP",
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: "Which of the following statements is TRUE about the OSI model?",
    options: [
      "It defines a physical standard for network communication.",
      "It is a theoretical model used for network design and troubleshooting.",
      "It only applies to wired networks, not wireless networks.",
      "It has seven layers, but not all layers are used in every network protocol.",
    ],
    answer:
      "It has seven layers, but not all layers are used in every network protocol.",
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question:
      "A network device that strengthens the signal and extends the range of a wireless network is called a:",
    options: ["Router", "Switch", "Repeater", "Firewall"],
    answer: "Repeater",
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question:
      "Which of the following statements about cloud computing is TRUE?",
    options: [
      "Cloud computing provides users with on-demand access to computing resources.",
      "Cloud computing requires users to install and maintain software on their devices.",
      "Cloud computing only offers storage solutions, not processing power.",
      "Cloud computing is a completely secure environment with no risk of data breaches.",
    ],
    answer:
      "Cloud computing provides users with on-demand access to computing resources.",
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question:
      "A(n) ____ cable is commonly used for connecting network devices over short distances.",
    options: ["Coaxial", "Fiber optic", "Cat5e", "Serial"],
    answer: "Cat5e",
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    question:
      "Which of the following devices operates at Layer 2 (Data Link Layer) of the OSI model. forwarding frames based on MAC addresses?",
    options: ["Router", "Switch", "Modem", "Firewall"],
    answer: "Switch",
  },
];
